Finding Aid for the Linda Farin papers, 1986-1989 LSC.1942
UCLA Library Special Collections
Linda Farin papers
1986-1997
bulk 1986-1989
UCLA Library Special Collections
Farin, Linda
LSC.1942
0.4 Linear Feet (1 document box)
Linda Farin was a successful lawyer in Austin, Texas. After seeing Donna Deitch's film Desert Hearts, she became inspired to produce a realistic and positive lesbian erotic film and began forming a cohort of lesbian writers in order to develop a script. This collection contains documentation relating to the production, distribution, and reception of the film Waking Up: A Lesson in Love.
Conditions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Linda Farin, 1990.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID:9969372173606533
Biographical Note
Linda Farin was a successful lawyer in Austin, Texas. After seeing Donna Deitch's film Desert Hearts, she became inspired and challenged to produce a realistic and positive lesbian erotic film and began forming a cohort of lesbian writers in order to develop a script. Through her participation with Liatris Media, which produced the Third Wave Women's International Film and Video Festival from 1986-1989, Linda Farin met Greta Schiller and Andrea Weiss. Greta Schiller became involved in the project in the early stages anonymously and later added her name to the project as Director. Farin formed both Foosh Productions and Anonymous Was a Woman Ltd. in order to help fund the project. Anonymous Was A Woman Ltd. was later dissolved in 1996.
Chronology
Missing Title
June 1985 Release of Before Stonewall: The Making of a Gay and Lesbian Community, Greta Schiller's first full length documentary.
May 1988 Foosh Productions Incorporated.
June 1988 Taping and production of Waking Up: A Lesson in Love
September 1988 Release of Waking Up: A Lesson in Love
Scope and Content
The Linda Farin Papers document the conception, production, distribution, and reception of the film Waking Up: A Lesson in Love, produced and co-written by Linda Farin. These papers include script drafts, financial documents, advertising strategies, copy reviews and correspondence.
Throughout the production of the film, funding issues as well as philosophical challenges arose from both within the circle of people working on the film as well as from the outside. In her story "The Making of a Lesbian Erotic Video" (contained within the collection), Lindsey Lane (co-writer and co-producer) outlines some of her frustrations with the effects of both homophobia and the difficulties of producing independent films. Much of the correspondence between reviewers and distributors reflects some of this conflict as well. While Waking Up: A Lesson in Love was produced in the late 1980's, the tensions of the "sex wars" of the late seventies and early eighties are present in the collection. Many of the reviewers and distributors approached by Linda Farin were generally uncomfortable with the portrayal of lesbian casual sex in the film in contrast to some of the more sex positive publications which chose to advertise and review the film such as On Our Backs magazine or Forum.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged chronologically.
Related Material
As of 1997, the film Waking Up: A Lesson in Love, was still available for purchase through Naiad Press, which is no longer in operation. The film is out of print and is held at the San Francisco Public Library, Cornell University Library, Michigan State University Library, and UCLA.
Lesbian motion picture producers and directors -- Archives.; Film scripts.; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives; University of California, Los Angeles. Library; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA; Farin, Linda -- Archives
- Film Festival Materials, 1986-1989; fliers; festival programs; submission guidelines (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Three years worth of promotional materials and programming information for Women's Visions: an International Film Festival in collaboration with Liatris media. The contents are for the years 1986 through 1989. The film festival operated annually through 1990 and was unique in its programming approach, showcasing women, gay and lesbian as well as third world artists.
- Production and Distribution Material, 1987; brochures; handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Includes price listings for deals with various distributors of lesbian film, erotica and/or books including Tiger Rose. Also includes production material such as budgets and shooting lists.
- Script Submissions, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Four script submissions including two copies of "Double Take" which has no attributions, one copy of "First Love Story" (an outline), one copy of "Cafe Au Lait" (a treatment by M. Llawger) and one copy of "20 Minutes Till Sex" by Jennifer Hoppe.
- Correspondence, 1987-1989; typewritten, copied and handwritten correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Contained is all correspondence relating to production, promotion, post production, contracts, expenses, fees and related disputes and distribution. Also included are discussions with various reviewers concerning content and feedback. Communication between those working on the film and those not working on the film is not separated as it was not in the original configuration of the collection.
- Script Drafts, 1987-1988; printed paper scripts, stapled (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Contains drafts of scripts as well as the final production script. Including: version one of "Love to Tell" by T. H. Fusch (pen name for Linda Farin), "Love to Tell: A Sensual Adventure in Three Acts" by Lindsey Lane and Linda Farin, "Love to Tell" and original screenplay by T.H. Fusch (third draft 5/31/1987), "Love to Tell" by Lindsey Lane and Linda Farin (copyright 1987 Foosh Productions, production script 6/6/88), two page 28 inserts, poem "Midnight Snack".
- Surveys and Distribution, 1988; printed paper with handwriting (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Eleven surveys furnished by Foosh Productions. The surveys solicited feedback about the film "Waking Up: A Lesson in Love" but also collected information such as: buying habits, reading/viewing habits, demographic information and market expectations. This folder also contains material from Foosh productions relating to distribution and marketing.
- Legal Documents, 1988; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Articles of incorporation for Foosh Productions Inc. Filed on 5/4/1988, Power of Attorney Documentation for Anonymous Was a Woman Ltd. (a Texas limited partnership), a subscription agreement and investment letter for Anonymous Was a Woman Ltd. and an Agreement and Certificate of Limited Partnership.
- Love To Tell Shooting Script and Schedules, 1988; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 8)
  The shooting script was revised 5/11/88 but still officially had the title of "Love to Tell" and contained three acts. Also contains a shooting schedule and crew contact list.
- Review Copy Tracking, 1988; handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Documents related to tracking copies of the VHS "Waking Up: A Lesson in Love" to various media outlets and publications for review.
- Waking Up Promotional Photos, circa 1988; photos; photocopies of photos; VHS sleeves; mounted photos (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Includes VHS sleeves in full color, some color enhanced photos by Minerva graphics, fourteen 8 by 10 glossy promotional stills, a proof sheet and various photos of unspecified sizes with cropping notes.
- Advertisements, 1988-1989; newspaper clippings; magazine clippings; handwritten notes; newsletters (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Clippings from advertisements placed in newsletters, papers and magazines for "Waking Up: A Lesson in Love". Includes some financial records of advertising costs and notes about advertising strategies and a list of places to publish advertisements. Also includes advertising mockups for "Waking Up"
- Distribution Agreements, 1988-1989; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Distribution agreements including financial details and agreements with companies, stores and mail order distributors including LBL video and Susan Wilson among others.
- Newspaper clippings, 1988-1997; newspaper clippings (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Includes: "The Making of a Lesbian Erotic Video" by Lindsey Lane published in the Austin Chronicle, September 30, 1988. Lindsey Lane was the co-writer and co-producer of "Waking Up: A Lesson in Love". the article is the difficulties that characterized the production of the video including securing funding as well as internalized and externalized homophobia that led to many involved keeping their participation anonymous./"Don't Ask, Don't tell Headed for Showdown: Supreme Court Could Decide its Fate in 97" by Rick Adde published in the Army Times, January 13, 1997./"Gay Friendly Synagogue Gets New Building: Inclusive Congregation Draws Many" published in Independent, January 21, 1997.
- Mail Orders, 1988-1990; letters; order forms (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Mail orders and requests for products from Foosh productions.
- Reviews and Events Listings, 1988-1989; newspaper clippings; magazines; fliers (Box 1, Folder 15)
  A collection of both published reviews of and listings for screenings or other related events of "Waking Up: a Lesson in Love". Reviews include: Gay Community News - September 4-10, 1988 - two clippings and 4 photocopies/ Au Courant - September 26, 1988 - one clipping/ Washington Blade - October 28, 1988 - one clipping/ Gay Chicago Magazine - January 12-22, 1989 - one clipping, two photocopies/ On Our Backs - January/February 1989 - one clipping, one photocopy of cover and one full issue/ FORUM - March 1989 by Susie Bright - one clipping, one cover Event Listing include: Gay Community News - September 11-14, 1988 - one clipping, one photocopy / This Week in Texas - September 30, 1988 - listing and cover/ Nexus flyer - October 4, 1988 - one flyer/ Dimensions - October 1988 - one issue/ Lambda Newletter - October 1988 - one newsletter/ Austin Chronicle - December 2, 1988 - one clipping/ Women and Their Work and Liatris Media - December 8, 1988 - one flyer/ Also included: four photocopies of anonymous viewer comments furnished by Foosh Productions as promotional material